人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
翻译   辰星晓Reginamoon   -小y   吃冰棒
彼得将会给你指路
Peter will point the way.
《失落的秘符》前情提要
Previously on "The Lost Symbol"...
他抓走了彼得
He's got Peter.
中情局  我以为联调局负责绑架案
CIA? I thought the Bureau handled kidnappings.
翻译    哈里不是波特   司柏   易碎的绝对
所以说这只手属于彼得·所罗门
So, this hand belonged to Peter Solomon.
彼得是我的导师
Peter was my mentor.
翻译    DerbyNinja   Caroline   冰岛豆腐
所罗门的孩子为我们工作过吗
Solomon's kid worked for us?
很短暂  三年期
Briefly. Three years ago.
他被殴打致死  在安卡拉
He was beaten to death. In Ankara.
校对    苏葵
尖顶石可以完善这段信息
The capstone could complete the message.
迈拉克需要你去找入口
Mal'akh needs you to find the portal.
时间轴    Caroline   爱说谎的孩子
我们还有很多工作要做  罗伯特
We have more work to do, Robert.
你的命运现在掌握在罗伯特的手中
Your fate is in Robert's hands now.
后期    MythCreator
如果我要帮助你爸爸  我就得走了
If I'm gonna help your dad, I got to go.
我要跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
总监    苏葵
地铁换乘
-那是什么  -镀金边
- What is that? - Gilded edges,
希伯来语...可能是经文
Hebrew... Probably a religious text.
[希伯来语]
我的希伯来语有点生疏了
Ah, my Hebrew's a little rusty.
行了  我有个应用
Okay, I have an app.
好吧  你从来不用谷歌
Right. 'Cause you never Google.
-我可没出声  -嗯  我看得懂你的表情
- I didn't say anything. - Yeah, I know your looks.
我在全球意识项目中
I work on the Global Consciousness Project
与来自世界各地的科学家共事
with scientists from all over.
这个应用救过我不止一次
This has saved me more than once.
《旧约》中的《列王纪上》  第三章
First Kings, chapter three. Old Testament.
《列王纪上》  第三章
First Kings, chapter three.
"所罗门王的审判"
Uh, the Judgement of Solomon.
兰登...
Langdon...
把手机扔了
他们可以追踪你们
什么  这是谁发来的
What? Who sent this?
越过行者去找狼
"越过行者去找狼"
"Pass the wayfarer. Find the wolf."
什么啊
What?
我们得走了
We should go.
-凯瑟琳  -怎么了
- Katherine.  - What?
你的手机
Your phone.
越过行者...
Pass the wayfarer...
你干什么
What are you doing?
去找狼
Find the wolf.
这儿有个门
There's a hatch here.
右边有个插销
There's a bolt to the left.
把它插上
Slide it over.
沃伦
Warren?
很高兴见到你  凯瑟琳
It's good to see you, Katherine.
很抱歉我们是在这种情况下见面
Sorry it's under these circumstances.
-手机  -我们丢了
- Phones? - We left them.
-很好  -有人想要和我解释一下吗
- Good. - Does someone want to tell me what's going on?
我们可以边走边聊
We can talk on the way.
失落的秘符
第一季第二集
是在哪里跟丢的
Where'd you lose him?
通往站台的隧道里
Tunnel, on the way to the platform.
我不知道  他上一秒还在  下一秒就不见了
I don't know. He was there, then he wasn't.
所罗门的女儿和他在一起
And Solomon's daughter was with him.
凯瑟琳吗
Katherine?
我们会继续找
We'll keep looking,
查看摄像头  梳理轨迹
check the cameras, comb the tracks.
-他们一定就在附近  -老大来了
- They've got to be close. - Boss is here.
有情况向我汇报
Keep me posted.
如今我们面临着怨声载道的员工
We're saying disgruntled employee.
工作场所的枪击
Workplace shooting.
-且无关政治  -是我的错
- Apolitical. - It's my fault.
我留他一个人了
I left him exposed.
你做了你应该做的
You did your job.
枪手是什么情况
What about the shooter?
清洁工叫尼古拉斯·巴斯庭  37岁
The janitor is Nicholas Bastin. 37.
机密信息
前军医  2015年光荣退伍
Former Army medic. Honorable discharge 2015.
无犯罪记录  政治立场不明确
No criminal record. Politically ambivalent.
六个月前  他失踪了
Six months ago, he goes off the grid.
-另一个呢  -没有线索  他就是个幽灵
- And the other one? - No hits. He's a ghost.
机密信息
除了在国会大厦留下了一只断手
And in addition to leaving a severed hand at the Capitol,
他还在一英里外的公园
he left two uniforms half-dead
把两位警察打得半死不活
in the park a mile away.
如果这之间有联系呢
What if there's a connection?
跟什么
To...?
扎克里·所罗门死于土耳其的监狱暴动
Zachary Solomon died in a prison riot in Turkey.
而杀他的凶手...
And whoever killed him...
机密信息
留下了这个
left this.
三曲腿图  这是共济会的重要符号
Triskelion. It's an important symbol in Freemasonry.
也许是你过度解读了
Or maybe you're reading too much into this.
你把它变成私人恩怨了
You're making it personal.
也许吧
Maybe.
你在国会大厦地下室发现的手工制品呢
And the artifact you found in the Capitol basement?
金字塔跟兰登一起消失了
The pyramid's gone. With Langdon.
那其中藏了很多秘密
And with it, many secrets.
我们听说过这个入口
We've heard of this portal.
我们对它
And we are interested in it
以及它可能蕴含的信息很感兴趣
and any information it might lead to.
但依我看
But from where I'm sitting,
我们似乎已经错过了找到它的最佳时机
it looks like our best chance to find it has flown the coop.
我们需要兰登
We need Langdon.
那彼得·所罗门呢
What about Peter Solomon?
我们可以双管齐下
We can walk and chew gum.
但我不会在这上面抱太大期望
But I would manage my expectations on that front.
彼得在阿拉弗
Peter is in the Araf.
穆斯林的炼狱
你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
天堂和地狱之间的分界线
The borderland between Heaven and Hell.
谢了  我知道阿拉弗是什么
Yeah, thank you. I know what the Araf is.
他是否能返回到你的世界
And whether he returns to your world
亦或直奔下一程
or moves on to the next
取决于你此刻的行动
will depend on your actions.
他可能已经死了
He might already be dead.
那通电话是用所罗门的手机打的
That call was made from Solomon's phone.
你在监听他吗
You were monitoring him?
我们监听很多人
We monitor a great many people.
找到兰登
Find Langdon.
我跟彼得当了30年朋友
I've been friends with Peter for 30 years.
共济会会友吗
Freemason friend?
《回头的行者》
"The Wayfarer."
博斯的一幅画  因涉及共济会闻名
A painting by Bosch known for its Masonic references.
抱歉发了这么多神秘信息
I'm sorry for all the cryptic texts,
我担心你的信息被监控了
but I was afraid your messages were being monitored.
是啊
Right.
那我们现在直接跟着你吗
So we're just supposed to follow you now?
-没问题  -我相信他
- No questions. - I trust him.
他就像我和扎克的叔叔
He was like an uncle to me and Zach.
这解释不了他怎么知道在哪能找到我们
Which doesn't explain how he knew where to find us.
我以前在国务院工作
I used to be with the State Department.
后来我有了新工作  国会大厦建筑师
Then I got a new job: Architect of the Capitol.
国会大厦建筑群
Which puts me in charge
所有的建筑都由我负责
of every building in the Capitol complex.
我知道这些楼里
I know everything that goes on
和楼底的一切情况
in these buildings and under them.
我们现在在国会图书馆的下方
We're under the Library of Congress now--
从前的流通书库
the old circulation room.
-这是...  -以前的传输系统
- So that's the, uh... - The old conveyor system.
它在另外两栋楼下传输书籍
It ran books under the other two buildings.
你们在这里很安全
Look, you'll be safe here.
这段时间低调行事
Just lay low for a bit.
低调行事  这对我爸有什么帮助
Lay low? How is that going to help Dad?
等到我们想出下一步计划
Just until we figure out our next steps.
我能看看吗
May I see it?
我用共济会密码
I used the Mason cipher
破译过  但...
to translate it, but...
这需要尖顶石才能破译
It requires the capstone to be understood.
你知道尖顶石
You know about the capstone.
你知道我们在哪能找到它吗
Do you know where we can find it?
不知道
No.
很久以前  共济会会长
Long ago, the Master Masons,
他们把金字塔和尖顶石
they hid the pyramid and the capstone
藏在两个不同的位置
in two different locations.
没人能同时知道
No one person is allowed to know
两者的位置
the location of both pieces.
我爸把这个藏在了保险箱
Dad kept this in his safe.
我们觉得这可能是条线索
We think it might be a clue.
出自《列王记》之《所罗门的审判》
It's from First Kings. The Judgment of Solomon.
只是老套
It's just your typical,
还有点烦人的圣经故事
moderately disturbing Bible tale.
我不知道他为什么要把这个放在保险柜里
I don't know why he'd keep it in a safe.
-我也不明白  -一定和某个
- Neither do I. - There has to be
我们都知道的故事有关
something about this beyond the story we all know.
如果是这样  我完全不知道
Well, if there is, I don't know about it.
休息吧
Rest.
我去找人调查
I'll press my contacts to find out
是否有你父亲下落的其他信息
if there's more information about your father.
凯瑟琳
Katherine...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你还有个手机
Extra phone?
不是我的
It's not mine.
之前在国会大厦
Back at the Capitol,
他们把我关在一间屋子里  有警卫看守
they had me in a room, under guard.
有个打扮成清洁工的人进来
A man came in dressed like a janitor.
他开枪杀了警卫  然后给了我这个
He shot the guards and gave me this.
迈拉克
Mal'akh.
他这么称呼对方
That's what he called him.
那个掳走彼得的人
The person who took Peter.
到底有多少人和这件事有关
How many people are a part of this?
我不知道
I don't know.
还有那只手
And the hand?
你怎么知道是我爸的
How do they know it was Dad's?
是他的戒指
It was his ring.
戒指可以调换
Well, a ring can be switched.
那只手是最近被斩断的
The hand had been severed... recently.
那还是不能证明是他的手
That still doesn't prove it was his.
你说得对
Y-You're right.
别来这套
No, don't do that.
不要顺着我的话说  我不会崩溃
Don't humor me. I'm not going to break.
我不知道该怎么说
I-I don't know what I'm supposed to say.
意料之中
That's not a surprise.
抱歉  我只是在消化这所有的事
I'm sorry. I'm just trying to process all of this.
我只是希望他能平安无事
I just need him to be okay.
我也是
Me, too.
逮捕令
扎克里·所罗门
贩毒
Trafficking?
什么意思
What does that even mean?
三年前
一般来说  这是指
Well, u-usually, it refers to, uh,
非法贩卖毒品
illegal trading, dealing narcotics...
这个案子中  在扎克里家中
In this case, a staggering amount of heroin
发现了大量海洛因
found in Zachary's apartment.
问题是  我们该怎么办
The question is, what are we going to do about it?
萨辛教授为人权观察组织
Professor Sahin wrote a study
写过一篇关于土耳其司法系统的研究
on the Turkish justice system for Human Rights Watch.
她在那可能有认识的人
She might have a contact.
或许他就需要这样的经历
Maybe this is just what he needs.
任由他烂在一个第二世界的监狱里吗
To rot in a decrepit, Second World prison?
自己的错自己承担  不能总指望有人会救他
To not be rescued from his own mistakes.
现在他需要的不是你的教训
He doesn't need your lessons right now.
他需要的是你的爱
He needs your love.
我给了他我的爱
I gave him my love.
他拒绝了
He rejected it.
你想要他和你一样
You wanted him to be just like you.
像你一样沉迷于这些无关紧要的事
To share in your obsession with all of this... trivia.
他拒绝的是这个
That's what he rejected.
但这并不意味着你不再是他的父亲
But it doesn't mean that you get to stop being his father.
我先失陪了
Excuse me.
你不会真的觉得我们应该把他丢在那吧
You don't really think we should leave him there.
罗伯特  我这样不公平吗
Robert, am I being unfair here?
你不必回答这个问题
You-you don't have to answer that.
我觉得你只是
I-I think you're just...
一个处境艰难的父亲
a father in a difficult situation,
我能理解
and I... I get that.
兰登  你要干什么
Langdon, what are you doing?
放开  他拿走了那页纸
Let go. He took the page.
我早就觉得他之前有所隐瞒
I thought he was holding something back before.
他知道为什么这个很重要
He knows why it's important.
是这样吗
Is that true?
我发过誓要保护它
I took an oath to protect it.
保护什么
Protect what?
古代奥义
The ancient wisdom.
我能理解你对此持怀疑态度
Look, I understand your skepticism...
是吗  你还真是心胸宽广
Do you? How generous.
可这里面还有别的事情
But there are other things at play here.
我知道这些故事  它们仅仅是故事而已
I know these stories. And that is all that they are.
比如共济会金字塔的神话
Take the myth of the Masonic pyramid,
建得如此之高  上帝都能一伸手就摸到它
built so high God could reach out and touch it.
你是在告诉我  这里说的就是这些吗
And you're telling me that's what they're talking about?
也许那些故事被刻意夸大了
Well, perhaps those stories were deliberately exaggerated.
为了什么
To what end?
为了让你这样的学者继续认为
So that academics like you would continue to believe
它们不过是神话
they're a myth.
就不会有人去寻找它们了
So no one would search for them.
这只是块石头
It's a piece of rock.
这是一幅地图
It's a map.
什么情况
What was that?
也许我们应该去楼上继续讨论
Maybe we should continue this discussion upstairs.
共济会中有个派别
There's a sect within the Masons.
规模很小  异常秘密
Very small and very secret.
利维坦社
The Leviathan Group.
我们的目的是确保
Our purpose is to make sure
古代奥义继续得以隐藏
that the ancient wisdom stays hidden,
直到世界做好准备的那一天
until such time as the world is ready.
这是彼得所希望的
This is what Peter wants.
那么他...他也宣誓加入你们了
So h-he also took your oath.
你说金字塔是幅地图  那是什么意思
You said the pyramid was a map. What does that mean?
据说把金字塔和尖顶石
It is said that, when brought together,
放到一起时
the pyramid and the capstone
它们会揭示出入口的位置
will reveal the location of the portal.
你觉得彼得会宁死来保护这个秘密
And you think Peter would die to keep this secret?
你有权坚守你的信仰  无论有多荒唐
You're entitled to your beliefs, as unhinged as they are,
但事关他的性命
but this is his life.
说起来  这个秘密奥义是什么啊
What is it, anyway, this secret wisdom?
是个...公式吗
Is it an... an equation?
一种祈祷
An invocation?
没人知道
No one knows.
至少活着的没人知道
No one living, at least.
这非常像爸爸的风格
Well, this is all very on-brand for Dad.
他总是说现代物理学
He'd always say that modern physics
仅仅是开始理解
was only starting to comprehend
古人们早已知道真实存在的东西
what the ancients knew to be true.
他是我从事这个工作的原因
He's why I do what I do.
他对你的工作非常骄傲
He's very proud of your work.
通灵能力的起源
The genetics of psychic ability,
集体意识...
collective consciousness...
很多人认为这是疯话
A lot of people think it's crazy.
但虽说我很确信我是正确的  他们是错的
But for all my certainty that I'm right and they're wrong,
我的意识里总有这么个微小的声音
there is always a subtle voice in my head,
有个疑虑
this doubt:
如果这不是真的呢
What if it's not real?
难道你不想知道这是不是真的吗
Don't you want to know if it's real?
我不清楚我该不该知道
I'm not sure I'm meant to know.
我看到你看那个金字塔的神情了
I saw the way you looked at that pyramid.
我了解那种神情
I know that look.
你可能再也不会有这种机会了
You may never get this chance again.
帮助我们找到它
Help us find it.
希伯来文...
The Hebrew...
是密码
It's code.
如果真的是  那一定有办法
If that's true, then there has to be a way
去破解它  一个密钥
to decipher it. A key.
对
Yes.
只有彼得有
And Peter's the only one that has it.
过程就是这样
That's how it goes.
一层面纱被揭开
One veil is lifted
露出来的不过是另一层面纱
only to reveal another.
他肯定会放在身边
He'd have it close.
放到他能看到的地方
Somewhere he can keep an eye on it.
甚至也许就在他身上
Maybe even on him.
我实验室保险柜的应急钥匙
Override key for the safe in my lab.
我时刻都戴着它
I keep it on me at all times.
-彼得戴什么首饰吗  -就一件
- Does Peter even wear jewelry? - Just one piece.
他的戒指
His ring.
你不戴你的吗
You don't wear yours.
只有在举行仪式时
Only for functions.
-很多共济会员都这样  -我爸爸不是
- A lot of Masons do that. - Not my dad.
他总是戴着它  总是
He always wears his. Always.
戒指很小  但并不意味着它没有隐藏着什么信息
It's small. It doesn't mean it's not concealing information.
问题是  它现在被放在
Problem is: it's in the possession
国会警察那里
of the Capitol Police.
我想这些地道不可能让我们潜入
I don't suppose these tunnels could sneak us
偷偷进入他们的证物房
into their evidence room.
这我就帮不了你们了
I can't help you with that.
也许我知道有人可以帮我们
I might know someone who can.
你知道这是用猪骨头做的吧
You know they make it out of pig bones, right?
明胶
Gelatin.
你是完全素食主义者吗
You a vegan?
当然不是  我吃肉
Hell no. I eat animals.
但是只吃肉  其他部分不吃
The meat parts, not the... other parts.
我可以给你拿点苹果酱
I could... get you some applesauce.
为什么全都是婴儿食品
Why all the baby food?
医生说子弹没打中任何重要部位
Doctor said the bullet didn't hit anything important.
但严格来说你还在手术恢复期
Still, you're technically recovering from surgery.
好吧  来点苹果酱吧
Okay, I'll take the applesauce.
这么快
That was quick.
不  等等
No, wait!
你醒了吗
You awake, awake?
You awake?
应该醒了
I think so.
有人来看你
You have a visitor.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
很好
Pretty good, you know?
医生说我一两天就可以出院了
Doc says I could be out in a day or two.
你的探员怎么样
How's your agent?
燕麦奶
Oat Milk.
他没活下来
He didn't make it.
该死  抱歉
Damn. Sorry.
你能告诉我他说了什么吗
Can you tell me what he said?
枪手  兰登的枪手
The shooter. To Langdon.
我不知道
I don't know.
一切都很...
It's all just...
没事  不必勉强
It's okay. Don't force it.
他是什么人  那个清洁工
Who is he? The janitor.
肯定有一些...
I mean, there's got to be...
监控录像  面部识别  指纹
video, facial recognition, fingerprints...
你查到他的身份了吗
You get an ID yet?
不能说
Can't say.
是我  记得吗
Hey, it's me, remember?
阻止巨墙把我们
The guy who stopped the giant wall
全都变成三明治的那个人
from turning us all into panini?
那个人来我的大楼
Dude came into my building.
那栋大楼
That building.
你知道我的意思吗
You know what I'm saying?
把名字告诉我
Give me a name.
好吧
Right.
这是个知其所需的世界
It's a need-to-know world.
好好休息吧
Get some rest.
把手机扔了  他们可以追踪你们
越过行者去找狼
有人在帮他们
Someone's helping them.
我还是不知道他们是怎么离开那里的
And I still don't know how they got out of there.
我们搜查了车站的四面八方
We swept the station in every direction.
-下面呢  -隧道吗
- What about down? - The tunnels?
没有公众能进入的入口
There's no public access.
这不是一个普通的公众
This isn't a public person.
我想他们可能掉了这个
Think they might've dropped this.
你在凯瑟琳父亲房子里发现她的时候
When you found Katherine in her father's house,
你搜她身了吗
did you search her?
没事
It's okay.
25街的国会发电厂
The Capitol Power Plant on 25th
应该能告诉我们谁能进入那些隧道
should be able to tell us who has access to the tunnels.
我现在就赶过去
I'll head over now.
你要去哪
Where you gonna be?
彼得·所罗门家
Peter Solomon's.
格兰特·西蒙斯
中情局特别探员
干得好
Well done.
我们需要更多的镇静剂
We'll be needing more sedative.
我去找我在医院的联络人
I'll go see my contact at the hospital.
除非你要我看着所罗门
Unless you need me looking after Solomon?
不用  没事
No, it's fine.
他跑不掉的
He isn't going anywhere.
信仰联合医疗中心
我不明白
I don't understand.
是政治原因吗
Was it political?
他是暴动者还是什么吗
Was he some kind of insurrectionist, or what?
不知道  他们正在想办法查清楚
I don't know. They're trying to figure it out.
四年了  我睡觉的时候
Look, for four years I went to sleep
都害怕你会被爆炸装置炸飞
afraid that you were gonna be blown up by an IED
或是头被人砍掉
or get your head chopped off.
我们在这里本应很安全
We're supposed to be safe here.
没事的
It's okay.
我现在很安全
I'm safe now.
抱歉  打扰一下
Sorry to interrupt.
-我要送他去做计算机断层扫描  -为什么
- I need to borrow him for a CAT scan. - For what?
我不需要更多伽马射线来扭曲我的DNA
I don't need any more gamma rays warping my DNA.
我又不想成为蜘蛛侠
I'm not trying to be Spider-Man over here.
是绿巨人
The Hulk.
伽马射线造出的是绿巨人
Gamma rays created the Hulk.
好吧
Okay.
我过会再来看你
I will see you later.
去吧
Go.
安吉拉在哪里
Where's Angela?
就是平常的那位护士
The usual nurse.
她生病回家了
Went home sick.
抱歉  先生  这位病人传染性极强
Sorry, sir, this patient's extremely contagious.
说什么呢
Say what now?
我中枪了  没有传染性
I got shot. I'm not infectious.
你们大概找错病人了
Maybe you got the wrong patient.
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
不是吧
Oh, hell no.
我进去看看就出来
Just gonna take a quick look.
中情局  你们今天可真忙
CIA. Busy day for you guys.
你朋友刚走
Your friend just left.
我想我知道凯瑟琳是从哪拿到那封信了
I think I know where Katherine got that envelope.
-信很重要吗  -不知道
- Is it important? - No idea.
你知道布莱克今天派其他人
Do you know if Blake sent anyone else
-去所罗门家了吗  -据我所知没有
- over to Solomon's house today? - Not that I know of.
你认为他派人跟踪你吗
You think he's got someone shadowing you?
我并不觉得意外
Wouldn't put it past him.
你在发电厂里找到了什么
What'd you find at the plant?
发电厂为国会大厦和其他22座建筑供电
So it services the Capitol and 22 other buildings.
其下有八千米的隧道
There's five miles of tunnel down there.
那么...
And...
我们知道谁有权进去吗
do we know who has access?
工程师  技术服务人员
Engineers, service techs,
三四名联邦特工
and three or four federal agents.
国会大厦的建筑师也能进去吗
Is the Architect of the Capitol one of them?
他的名字叫做沃伦·贝拉米
His name's Warren Bellamy.
沃伦·贝拉米
是的
Yeah.
你怎么知道的
How'd you know that?
告诉我他的电话
Get me his phone.
以及所有信息
Get me everything.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
他们正找你  伙计
They're looking for you, man.
如果有其他选择  我们也不会来这里
We wouldn't be here if we had any other options.
"我们"指的是谁
Who's "we," anyway?
我是凯瑟琳·所罗门
I'm Katherine Solomon.
彼得的女儿
Peter's daughter.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
你父亲的事我很遗憾
And-and I-I'm sorry.
-谢谢  -我们的时间不多了
- Thanks. - We don't have a lot of time.
-你们需要我做什么  -我们需要那个戒指
- What do you need from me? - We need the ring.
他手上戴的那个
From his hand.
那个戒指是物证  在市中心一个储物柜里
The ring. That's evidence. It's in a locker downtown.
你能给谁打电话  把戒指拿出来吗
Could you call someone? Ask to get it released?
可以  就像外卖  也许来点蛋卷
Sure, yeah, like takeout. Maybe get some egg rolls.
你得派人进去签字领取
You'd have to have someone go in and sign it out.
没有戒指我们只能凑合
We'll have to make do without it.
我们没有其他选择
Well, we don't have any other options.
你们到底要戒指干什么
What do you need it for, anyway?
有一页记录着《旧约》中
There's this page from the Old Testament,
所罗门王故事的纸
the story of Solomon.
我们认为它被编码过  那枚戒指可能包含
We think it's encoded and that the ring could contain
某种解密秘钥
some type of decryption key...
行  好的  就说到这吧
Yeah, okay, that's fine.
他会继续说下去  对吗
He goes on, doesn't he?
听着
Look.
佐藤之前来看过我
Sato came to see me earlier.
你们说得对
And you were right,
她有什么事瞒着我们
there's something she's hiding from us.
我能在处理一些秘密
I can deal with secrets to a point,
但当那家伙开枪后  我就受不了了
but I passed that point when that guy started shooting.
好吧
Okay.
我们得去趟洗衣店
We'll need to head by the cleaners.
我在那里还有一套制服
I got another uniform there.
车不错
Nice ride.
是我朋友的车
It belongs to a friend.
是吗  他是干什么的
Yeah? What's he do?
建筑师
Architect.
信仰联合医疗中心
不管那么多了
Here goes nothing.
我要是二十分钟没出来
If I'm not out in 20 minutes,
你们就报警
call the cops.
你打算怎么跟你妈妈说
What are you going to tell your mom?
什么也不说
Nothing.
她好不容易情绪稳定了
She's finally in a relatively stable place,
所以我...
so I, um...
我不能把这些告诉她  现在不行
I can't tell her about this. Not yet.
我应该去实验室签到
I should check in at the lab.
我的手机还在小费盒里
And my phone is in a tip jar.
假装现在是七十年代
Just pretend it's the '70s.
-前蜂窝时代  -就不能是八十年代吗
- Pre-cellular. - Can it be the '80s?
前蜂窝  第一代蜂窝电话的前身
八十年代...
The '80s...
对  那些绝妙的音乐
Yeah. Great music.
从各种文化角度来看
By every cultural measure,
七十年代才是更好的十年
the '70s was the better decade.
光是电影...
The films alone...
什么  八十年代也有精彩的电影
What? The '80s had amazing movies.
《外星人》  《回到未来》
"E.T.," "Back to the Future,"
-《威洛》...  -的确
- "Willow"... - Yeah.
但我说的是一些成熟的电影
I'm talking about grown-up films.
《教父》  《电视台风云》  《唐人街》
"Godfather," "Network," "Chinatown"...
《掠夺者》
"Raiders."
《掠夺者》  《掠夺者》  好吧
"Raiders." "Raiders," okay.
我们也有过愉快的几个月  不是吗
We had a few good months, right?
直到我的家庭爆炸
Before my family exploded
并把所有人都卷入了危机
and we got caught in the blast radius?
十个半月
Ten and a half.
你有很多事情要做
You had a lot going on.
我爸跟你说过那件事吗
Does Dad ever talk to you about it?
关于扎克吗
About Zack?
没有  和你呢
No. You?
没有
No.
我感觉他认为
I feel like he thinks
我会为所发生的事责怪他
I blame him for what happened.
这很艰难
You know, it's hard.
我不知道还有这些事
I didn't know that was going on.
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
我只是想见见他
I just want to see him,
告诉他那不是他的错
so I can tell him it wasn't his fault.
一想到我可能没有机会
The thought that I might not get the chance
告诉他这一点...
to tell him that is...
凯瑟琳
Katherine.
你会有机会的
You're gonna get the chance.
我保证
I promise.
我只是需要他知道我爱他
I just need him to know that I love him.
他不能像扎克那样结束
It can't end with him the way it did with Zach.
特别的凯
Special K.
看起来真有教养
Looking very civilized.
我真惊讶他们居然让你进来了
I'm surprised they even let you in.
罗伯特认识的一个人
Robert knew someone
帮我走了走后门
who, uh, helped me pull some strings.
你还和那个傻瓜在一起吗
You're still with that twat?
你的脚怎么了
What happened to your feet?
我在这里
Well, I was having
遇到了一些人际关系问题
some interpersonal issues in here,
有谣言说我可能会试图逃跑
and there was a rumor I might try to escape.
所以警卫们要确保我跑不了
So the guards made sure I couldn't.
他们不能这么对你
They can't do this to you.
为什么
Why?
因为人权吗
Human rights?
你来错地方了  凯
You're in the wrong part of town, K.
我们得把你弄出去
We have to get you out of here.
-我们吗  -是的
- We? - Yes.
你有过机会
You had your chance!
爸本可以一个电话就把我救出去
Dad could have gotten me out with one phone call.
但我只收到了一封信
Instead, I got a letter.
"我不会允许你
"I won't allow you to play victim
在自己一手造成的情况下扮演受害者"
to circumstances you alone created."
你听到了吗
Did you hear about that?
我说这些干什么
What am I saying?
说不定还是你帮忙写的
You probably helped write it.
不  我反对他的做法
No. I didn't agree with him.
你反对了啊
Oh, you disagreed.
胆真大
How bold.
我敢说  你立场一定很坚定
Really stood your ground, I bet.
很高心你能来
I'm glad you came.
你可以帮我带个口信给他
You can give him a message for me.
我不再是他的儿子了
I'm not his son anymore.
是这个吗
This the one?
是的
Yeah.
好极了  我现在需要躺下了
Great. I'm-a go lie down now.
扎克里·所罗门
1987年生  2018年卒
这是什么
What's this?
《希伯来圣经》  1814年发行
Hebrew Bible. Published 1814.
有三个部分  第一部分是《妥拉经》
It's in three parts. The first part is the Torah.
两千年来  这三十万字只字未改
300,000 letters unchanged in over 2,000 years.
犹太人保存经文的传统毋庸置疑
The Jewish tradition of preserving text is uncompromising.
如果抄写员被发现增加  删减
If a scribe is found to have added, subtracted
或修改了一个字母
or altered a letter,
整篇手稿都将作废并被掩埋
the whole manuscript is invalidated and buried.
看
Look.
这里
Here.
这一整段  希伯来语变了
This entire section-- the Hebrew has been changed.
那意味着  这页是假的吗
So, what, the page is fake?
不  被篡改了
No, doctored.
用来隐藏信息
To hide a message.
仔细看这里
Look at it closely.
你能看出有什么问题吗
Can you see anything unusual about it?
看起来没什么问题
Well, looks normal enough.
所有必备的标记都有
All the requisite markings are here:
双头鹰  三角形...
the double-headed eagle, triangle, the...
等等
Oh, wait a minute.
这里应该是י
This is supposed to be a yod,
但这是ה
but it's a he.
什么
What?
这里的标记  珠宝商的失误吗
Yeah, this mark on it. A jeweler's mistake?
你觉得这看上去像什么
What does that look like to you?
π
Pi.
那可不是错误  而是索引
That is not a mistake, it's a cipher.
派
Pi.
3.1415926...
你背了圆周率
You memorized pi?
一部分
Part of it.
大学期间参加过一次比赛
Did a competition in college once.
背到了第417位
Got to the 417th character.
只背了417位吗
Only 417?
我当时饿了
I got hungry.
好了  那么从这里开始
Okay. So, starting from there,
第一个数字是3
first number's three.
圈出第3个字母
Circle the third character.
-然后是1  圈出第4个  -好的
- Then one, circle the fourth. - Okay.
4  圈第8个  以此类推
Four, circle the eighth. And so on.
好了  我们有14个字母组成了...
Okay, so we have 14 letters that spell...
我看看
Let see.
什么都不是  毫无意义
Nothing. It's a jumble.
肯定还有其他的步骤
There must be another step.
一层面纱后是又一层面纱
One veil lifts to reveal another.
未知联系人
接电话
否则承担后果
你认识这个号码吗
Do you recognize the number?
不
No.
你好
H-Hello?
很好  我的短信起作用了
Oh, good, my text worked.
我总是把未知电话转到语音信箱  所以...
I always send unknown calls to voice mail, so...
你是谁
Who is this?
佐藤井上  中情局的
Inoue Sato, with Central Intelligence.
我并无恶意  我想跟罗伯特谈谈
I'm a friend. I was hoping to talk to Robert.
什么罗伯特...
Uh, Robert...?
我们没时间了  贝拉米先生
We don't have time, Mr. Bellamy.
彼得有麻烦了
Peter's in trouble.
我不想再有人受伤了
I don't want anyone else getting hurt.
-你好  -兰登
- Hello? - Langdon.
你以为你在做什么
What do you think you're doing?
我想帮助彼得
I'm trying to help Peter.
你会害了你自己
You're going to get yourself hurt.
或者凯瑟琳
Or Katherine.
我这是给你机会自己出来  不然
I'm giving you a chance to come out on your own, or...
罗伯特
Robert?
我们走
Let's go.
你挂了中情局的电话
You just hung up on the CIA.
他们在外面
They're, uh, outside.
那我们快走
Let's go.
等下
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
该死  有人从隧道进来
Damn. Somebody's coming through the tunnels.
还有别的出路吗
Is there any other way out?
这里可以吗
What about this?
那是老运输系统
That's the old conveyor system.
我知道  你说这里通向其他建筑  对吗
I know. You said it goes to the other buildings, right?
这个系统很多年没用过了
The system hasn't been in use for years.
-但还能用吗  -值得一试
- But does it still work? - It's worth a shot.
你想让我们走这里
You want us to go in there?
罗伯特  不会有事的
Robert, it'll be okay.
我先进去
I'll go first.
以防万一
In case of emergency.
抱歉  图书馆关门了
I'm sorry, but the library's closed.
他们在哪
Where are they?
你还好吗
You doing okay back there?
还有多远
How much further?
不远了  我能看到光
It's not far. I can see the light.
我什么都看不到  我没睁开眼睛
I can't see anything, my eyes are closed.
尽量放松  享受其中
Just try to relax and enjoy the ride.
糟糕
Oh, no.
没事
It's okay.
糟了
Oh, no.
没事
It's okay.
你不会有事的
You'll be okay.
救救我  我卡住了
Help me! I'm stuck!
罗伯特
Robert?
救命
Help!
罗伯特
Robert.
救命
Help!
罗伯特
Robert.
你没事
You're okay.
我们爬过去
We're gonna crawl.
不远了
It's not that far.
你可以做到
You can do this.
好吗
Okay?
停车
Stop, hey!
Stop.
我的天
Oh, my God.
-你受伤了吗  -没  我没事
- Are you hurt? - No. I'm fine.
我没事  我没事
I'm good. I'm good.
好的
Okay, um...
我去前面看看  确保没人
I'm gonna go check up ahead, make sure it's clear.
好
Yeah.
来电
喂
Hello?
看样子你找了个旅行搭档
I understand you've picked up a fellow traveler.
我在照你的意思做
I am doing what you wanted.
我叫你单独行动
You were told to do it alone.
我不能让你被感情影响
No, I can't have you distracted by emotions.
甩掉她
Cut her loose.
不然我叫别人替你动手
Or I'll have someone do it for you.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
你好
Hello?
我能用下你手机吗
Can I use your phone, please?
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
还有很多事要做
There's more to be done.
他在哪
Where is he?
彼得在阿拉弗
Peter is in the Araf.
天堂和地狱之间的分界线
The borderland between Heaven and Hell.
他是否能返回到你的世界
Whether he returns to your world
亦或直奔下一程
or moves on to the next
取决于你的行动
will depends on your actions.